# Thomas OConnor

# Face to face client engagement is my specialty

Las Vegas, NV 89129 oconnor6555@gmail.com 702-308-0356

Senior IT, Managed Services, and Sales professional with over 30 years experience in meeting the technology and services needs of new and established businesses.

Experienced in managing both Inside Sales and Outside Sales Teams

Hands on experience developing channel and reseller programs Demonstrated self-starter with industry contacts

Enterprise Server, Storage, and PC Products (including Notebooks, and Tablets and rugged Mobility) sales experience within channel related accounts as well as major end user customers.

Proven success in building new sources of revenue with channel partners and direct end users while maintaining a current customer base.

Connections with application solution providers for a wide variety of project based business.

Effective communication skills - both written and verbal.

Ability to deliver convincing technical presentations and

demonstrations to customer audiences of varying sizes.

High degree of computer application proficiency with Microsoft Office Suites of products.

Excellent Interpersonal skills

Ability to travel.

Working knowledge of Salesforce.com, Microsoft Dynamics, and Sage SalesLogix

Ability to develop and maintain various types of relationships within large enterprise accounts (C level, SVP, VP, Director level)
Ability to lead large, complex project based opportunities.

## #readytowork

Willing to relocate to: Tucson, AZ - Albuquerque, NM - Montgomery, AL Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## Work Experience

#### **Director Of Business Development**

Integration Technologies, Inc - Las Vegas, NV December 2018 to March 2019

#### Area

Expand company footprint in the Las Vegas market. Developed customer

outreach and acquisition campaigns and implemented "best practices" for company CRM tools. Loss of key personnel led to shut down of Las Vegas

initiative.

Position eliminated.

**IONIZION IT** 

# **Vice President Sales and Support**

NVIZION IT - Las Vegas, NV April 2018 to November 2018

Brought on to kick start the company's sales and marketing outreach.

Redesigned website, created and implemented internal processes, and designed a customer acquisition process.

Increased company's social media presence through LinkedIn, Facebook, and Twitter.

Position eliminated

#### **Associate Director of Sales**

LegalMatch - Las Vegas, NV October 2017 to December 2017

#### Area

Lead a team of sales professionals in matching legal services consumers with attorneys nationwide. LegalMatch is a private U.S. corporation established in 1999 as a free, online legal matching service to help people find prescreened local lawyers, and to help attorneys get leads matching their legal specialty.

## **Sales Manager**

H and H Enterprises - Las Vegas, NV August 2016 to June 2017

#### Area

Led an Inside Sales Team of 7 in the sale and marketing of promotional products to the Enterprise and SMB markets. Developed new sales metric reporting and increased sales effectiveness 12%

#### **Strategic Account Manager**

Vanguard Integrity Professionals - Las Vegas, NV June 2016 to September 2016

## Area

Inside sales of Cyber Security and reporting software to the Fortune 500 for IBM z/OS mainframe systems. Full solutions include the sale of Professional Services as well.

## **Director of Business Development**

Complete Tablet Solutions - Long Beach, CA January 2015 to June 2016

Develop and maintain relationships with mobility partner hardware, software, and services community to enhance the market reach of a premier mobility

solutions provider. Work with inside and outside sales personnel to increase sales and grow market awareness.

# Manager, Sales and Reseller Channels

Quest International - Irvine, CA July 2014 to November 2014

Managed the Inside, Outside, and Reseller channels for Quest. Developed company first new hire and continuing education program. Responsible for all sales hiring decisions and attainment. Managed a team of 12 sales professional including Customer Relations Specialists.

## **Senior National Business Development Manager**

Panasonic System Communication Company North America April 2011 to April 2014

3 years 1 month)

Recruit and manage partners that leverage their "best of breed" products alongside Panasonic's award winning technologies and services. Excellent relationship builder with deep knowledge of the ISV/IHV space. Managed contracted Inside Sales Team for lead and revenue generation.

#### Education

## Associate in Liberal Arts and Sciences/Liberal Studies

**DePaul University** 

### **Technical Certificate in Telecommunications**

Community College of the Air Force - Las Vegas, NV

#### Skills

- Business development
- MSP
- Microsoft Office
- CRM Software
- Marketing
- Management Experience
- Public Speaking
- Product Management
- Outside Sales
- Account Management
- Sales Management
- Business Analysis
- Sage
- Inside Sales
- Product Development
- Salesforce

- Branding
- Telecommunication
- · Project Management
- · Market Research
- B2B Sales

## Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/thomas-oconnor-46965b2?jobid=1234&lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage %3Ad\_jobs\_easyapply\_pdfgenresume%3B8OGA%2BfOlSniJpPEVAX3iWg%3D%3D&licu=urn%3Ali %3Acontrol%3Ad\_jobs\_easyapply\_pdfgenresume-v02\_profile

# Military Service

**Branch: United States Air Force** 

Service Country: United States

Rank: E5

September 1973 to March 1981

Served as A Telecommunications center Specialist/Manager.

#### Certifications and Licenses

#### driver's license

#### Assessments

# Management & Leadership Skills: Impact & Influence — Highly Proficient

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to adapt their leadership style to accomplish goals using rational or emotional appeal.

Full results: Highly Proficient

# Management & Leadership Skills: Impact & Influence — Expert

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to adapt their leadership style to accomplish goals using rational or emotional appeal.

Full results: Expert

# Sales Skills: Influence & Negotiation — Highly Proficient

November 2018

Measures a candidate's ability to effectively use influence and negotiation techniques to engage with and persuade customers.

Full results: Highly Proficient

## Marketing — Highly Proficient

November 2019

Understanding a target audience and how to best communicate with them

Full results: Highly Proficient

# Sales: Influence & Negotiation — Highly Proficient

November 2019

Persuading reluctant customers to buy products or services, and influencing and negotiating with customers to meet sales goals.

Full results: Highly Proficient

# Accounting Skills: Bookkeeping — Familiar

November 2019

Calculating and determining the accuracy of financial data.

Full results: Familiar

## Search Engine Optimization — Proficient

November 2019

Interpreting online website performance metrics and understanding search engine optimization tactics

Full results: Proficient

# Management & Leadership Skills: Planning & Execution — Completed

November 2019

Planning and managing resources to accomplish organizational goals.

Full results: Completed

#### **Data Analysis — Completed**

November 2019

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data.

Full results: Completed

#### CRM Skills with Salesforce — Proficient

November 2019

Knowledge of Salesforce objects, fields, and processes.

Full results: Proficient

## **Logic & Verbal Reasoning — Proficient**

November 2019

Understanding the meaning of text, and identifying the relationships among words or concepts.

Full results: Proficient

#### **Legal Skills — Familiar**

November 2019

Assisting practicing attorneys in the preparation for litigation proceedings

Full results: Familiar

### Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Proficient

November 2019

Excel knowledge including common tools, PivotTables, conditional & nested formulas, and custom

visuals.

Full results: Proficient

# **Problem Solving — Highly Proficient**

November 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to analyze relevant information when solving problems

Full results: Highly Proficient

## **Logic & Critical Thinking — Proficient**

November 2019

Using logic to solve problems.

Full results: Proficient

#### **Customer Service Skills — Proficient**

November 2019

Measures a candidate's skill in evaluating approaches to customer service & satisfaction.

Full results: Proficient

#### **Outside Sales — Proficient**

December 2019

Actively listening and responding appropriately; performing common sales calculations.

Full results: Proficient

# **Customer Service Fit — Familiar**

March 2020

Measures the traits that are important for high-quality customer service.

Full results: Familiar

#### Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Proficient

May 2020

 $\label{thm:conditional and custom} \textbf{Excel knowledge including common tools, PivotTables, conditional \& nested formulas, and custom}$ 

visuals.

Full results: Proficient

### Management & Leadership Skills: Impact & Influence — Expert

May 2020

Choosing the most effective strategy to inspire and influence others to meet business objectives.

Full results: Expert

#### Sales: Influence & Negotiation — Highly Proficient

April 2020

Persuading reluctant customers to buy products or services, and influencing and negotiating with customers to meet sales goals.

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

#### **Phone Interview — Completed**

April 2020

Listen to candidates' responses to key questions to assess their experience, motivation, and people skills

Full results: Completed

### **Call Center Customer Service — Proficient**

April 2020

Applying customer service skills in a call center setting.

Full results: Proficient

## **Customer Focus & Orientation — Expert**

April 2020

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity

Full results: Expert

### **Business Analyst — Proficient**

May 2020

Analyzing information to solve business problems

Full results: Proficient

# **Customer Service — Completed**

December 2020

Identifying and resolving common customer issues

Full results: Completed

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

## Additional Information

Top Skills
Solution Selling
Channel Partners
Business Development